Cadillac Records is a drama, history, music film directed by Darnell Martin.
The story of sex, violence, race and rock and roll in 1950s Chicago, and the exciting but turbulent lives of some of America's
musical legends, including Muddy Waters, Leonard Chess, Little Walter, Howlin' Wolf, Etta James and Chuck Berry.
Leonard Chess, played by Adrien Brody.
Muddy Waters, played by Jeffrey Wright.
Geneva Wade, played by Gabrielle Union.
Little Walter, played by Columbus Short.
Willie Dixon, played by Cedric the Entertainer.
Revetta Chess, played by Emmanuelle Chriqui.
Cadillac Records is a 2008 American biographical drama
film written and directed by Darnell Martin.
The film explores the musical era from the early 1940s to the late 1960s, chronicling the life of the influential
Chicago-based record-company executive Leonard Chess, and a few of the musicians who recorded for Chess Records.
The film stars Adrien Brody as Leonard Chess, Jeffrey Wright as Muddy Waters, Columbus Short as Little Walter, Cedric the
Entertainer as Willie Dixon, Eamonn Walker as Howlin' Wolf, Mos Def as Chuck Berry, and Beyoncé Knowles as Etta James.
The film was released in North America on December 5, 2008, by TriStar Pictures.
The soundtrack was released on Music World/Columbia and Sony Music.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois, woman director, music.
The tone is emotional.